<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tmcn on Anything Data</title>
    <link>/tags/tmcn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tmcn on Anything Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tmcn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting Word Bigrams with 3 Chinese Classics</title>
      <link>/post/plotting-word-bigrams-with-3-chinese-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/plotting-word-bigrams-with-3-chinese-classics/</guid>
      <description>In the last post, we saw frequencies of the most common words in the Analects, Zhuangzi, and Mozi texts. The faceted plot did an excellent job of capturing a generic “theme” of each text. However, I wondered how the results might change when plotting bigrams (2 word combinations of adjacent words) as opposed to single values.
This is where I ran into a problem with Tidytext – although it worked fine for tokenizing Chinese text into single character tokens, it did not perform as well at separating the text into bigrams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tidytext Analysis of 3 Chinese Classics</title>
      <link>/post/a-quasi-tidytext-analysis-of-3-chinese-classics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-quasi-tidytext-analysis-of-3-chinese-classics/</guid>
      <description>For a long time I’ve admired the tidytext package and its wonderful companion book Text Mining with R. After reading it I thought, “Why not undertake a project of Chinese text analysis?” I am deeply interested in Chinese philosophy but I decided to keep the analysis narrow by selecting just three works - The Analects, Zhuangzi, and the Mozi.
Following similar pace with Tidytext, I first download my data. Here I use my package ctextclassics and specifically, the function get_books(c(.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>